

### CONTACT

+251945224486

wendiradame@gmail.com

Ethiopia, Oromia, Adama



@wendirad



@wendirad-demelash



wendirad.github.io

#### SKILLS



# django







### EDUCATION

Adama Science and Technology University

# Computer Science and Engineering

2018/19 - 2022/23

Adama Science and Technology University

# Electronics and Communication Engineering

2018/19 - 2022/23

-----

### LANGUAGES

English: Fluent

Amharic: Native

# WENDIRAD DEMELASH

### PYTHON DEVELOPER

### PROFILE

A Python developer with 3+ years of experience is a seasoned professional with a strong understanding of Python programming and has applied this knowledge to develop software applications and systems. As a Python developer, I have likely worked on a variety of projects, ranging from web development and data analysis to machine learning and artificial intelligence. With my experience, I have developed a strong understanding of software development methodologies, tools, and best practices. I am able to apply this knowledge to create high-quality software that meets the needs of users and businesses.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Python Developer**

#### Turing .inc

November 2022 - Present | Full time

As a Python Developer at a US-based company, my role is to develop code toward the company's mission of ensuring AI technology benefits all mankind. I solve numerous puzzles daily by writing high-quality, optimized Python code with minimal supervision. I work in a fast-paced environment that handles millions of production requests per day by leveraging advanced systems and APIs. Additionally, I provide clear explanations of logic in my code, handle complex situations, debug, create documentation, and conduct peer code reviews.

### **Full Stack Developer**

### **Backos Technologies**

January 2019 - November 2022 | Full time

As a Full Stack Developer at Backos Technology, I have 4 years of experience in developing and maintaining web applications using Python and Django. My responsibilities included designing and implementing new features, fixing bugs, and improving the performance and scalability of existing code. I have worked with a variety of programming languages and frameworks, including Python, Django, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I have also collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure that the applications I worked on met the needs of the business and delivered a great user experience.

## **Full Stack Web Developer**

February 2022 - January 2023 | Contract

### **Divergent Technologies**

As a Full Stack Developer at Divergent Technology, I was involved in the development of a web solution for the education sector focused on Al and Machine Learning. My responsibilities included gathering requirements, building SRS, designing system architecture, and implementing both front-end and back-end features.

## **Full Stack Web Developer**

### ASTU, SoEEC

May 2022 - October 2022 | Contract

As a Full Stack Developer at ASTU, I was involved in the development of a store management system for the School of Electrical Engineering and Computing (SoEEC). My responsibilities included designing and implementing features to verify stock balance, track item borrow history, manage university instructors' activity in stores, digitize item borrow request process, and manage reports and analytics.